Donald Barthelme, Sr. Architectural Papers, 1924-1997
University of Houston Libraries
- Teaching: University of Houston
  - Class Notes (Box 11)
    - Dittos, Master File, First Year, Pts. 1-11, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 5-15)
    - Dittos, Master File ARC 131D, Pts. 1-9, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 16-24)
    - Architectural Theory, Outline, Pts. 1-5, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 25-29)
    - Concepts, Miscellaneous Backup, Pts. 1-2, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 30-31)
    - Design - Notes, Pts. 1-2, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 32-33)
    - Ideas, Pts. 1-3, ca. 1967 (Box 11, Folder 34-36)
    - Diagrams, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Abstracts (Readings), Pts. 1-5, 1960-1971 (Box 11, Folder 38-42)
    - ARC 334 Research (Concepts), Pts. 1-6, 1966-1973 (Box 11, Folder 43-48)
    - Exercises, ARC 131D, Pts. 1-8, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 49-56)
    - Exercises, 131D, Pts. 1-6, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 57-62)
    - Ditto Index, Fall 1972, Pts. 1-3, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
    - Ditto Index, Spring 1973, Pts. 1-2, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - Notebook Series, Pts. 1-4, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 6-9)
    - Index, Miscellaneous, Pts. 1-3, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 10-12)
    - Miscellaneous Indexes, Pts. 1-7, 1946-1971 (Box 12, Folder 13-18)
    - Master Set, Spring, 1970, Pts. 1-9, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 20-28)
    - ARC 130, Intro I, Notebook, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Handouts, ARC 131D, Pts. 1-5, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 30-34)
    - Notebook Series #1, Pts. 1-5, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 35-39)
    - Study Series #1, Pts. 1-5, 1967-1972 (Box 12, Folder 40-44)
    - Study Series #2, Pts. 1-4, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 45-48)
    - Reading: Mechanics and Assignments, Pts. 1-5, 1966-1972 (Box 12, Folder 49-53)
    - Reading: Bibliographies Issues, Pts. 1-2, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 54-55)
    - Reading Assignments, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Program Administration, Pts. 1-3, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 57-59)
    - Reading Programs, Pts. 1-4, 1971-1972 (Box 12, Folder 60-63)
    - Class Notes, Intro II, Spring 1973, Pts. 1-4, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
    - Concepts Lectures, Spring 1972, Pts. 1-12, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 5-16)
    - Concepts, Ideas I, Pts. 1-14, 1965-1971 (Box 13, Folder 17-30)
    - Concepts, Ideas II, Pts. 1-11, 1965-1971 (Box 13, Folder 31-41)
    - Concepts, Design I, Pts. 1-7, 1967-1971 (Box 13, Folder 42-48)
    - ARC 320, Intro II, Pts. 1-6, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 49-54)
    - Professional Practice I, Pts. 1-11, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 55-65)
    - Practice: Reference Materials for Lectures, Pts. 1-11, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 66-76)
    - Concepts: Form, Pts. 1-7, 1966-1971 (Box 14, Folder 1-7)
    - Concepts: Your Place in Architecture, Pts. 1-2, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 8-9)
    - Concepts: Mechanics, Pts. 1-17, 1968-1971 (Box 14, Folder 10-16)
    - Concepts: Order, Pts. 1-4, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 17-20)
    - Concepts: Form, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Concepts: Future and Doxiadis, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Concepts: Sequence, Pts. 1-2, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 23-24)
    - Concepts: Whole v. Parts, Pts. 1-3, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 25-27)
    - Concepts: Change, Chance, Choice, Pts. 1-6, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 28-33)
    - Concepts: Order, Pts. 1-7, 1965-1971 (Box 14, Folder 34-40)
    - Concepts: Man I, Pts. 1-8, 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 41-48)
    - Concepts, Pts. 1-12, 1966-1971 (Box 14, Folder 49-60)
    - Examples, Pts. 1-2, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 61-62)
    - Object vs. Environment, Old Notes, Pts. 1-3, 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 63-65)
    - Concepts-Old Lectures, Pts. 1-13, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 66-78)
    - Concepts: Enclosure, Pts. 1-7, 1964-1972 (Box 15, Folder 1-7)
    - Concepts: Diagrams, Pts.1-3, 1964-1971 (Box 15, Folder 8-10)
    - Concepts: Space, Pts. 1-13, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 11-23)
    - Concepts IV: Human Performance, Pts. 1-8, 1963-1971 (Box 15, Folder 24-31)
    - Concepts II: Object, Pts. 1-6, 1963-1971 (Box 15, Folder 32-37)
    - Concepts: General, Pts. 1-5, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 38-42)
    - Concepts: Notes, Pts. 1-2, 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 42-44)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures, Pts. 1-2, 1963-1972 (Box 15, Folder 45-46)
    - Concepts: Notes (Miscellaneous Lectures), Pts. 1-3, 1959-1971 (Box 15, Folder 47-49)
    - Concepts: Notes, Pts. 1-6, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 50-55)
    - Concepts: Ideas, Pts. 1-2, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 56-57)
    - Concepts: Lectures, Pts. 1-16, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 58-73)
    - Core Discussion: Concepts, Pts. 1-5, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 1-5)
    - Core Discussion: Learning, Pts. 1-3, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
    - Core Discussion: Personal, Pts. 1-3, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 9-11)
    - Core Discussion: Demonstrations, Pts. 1-2, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
    - Core Discussion: Architecture, Pts. 1-7, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 14-20)
    - Core Discussion: Design, Pts. 1-5, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 21-25)
    - Core Discussion: Ideas, Pts. 1-3, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 26-28)
    - Core Discussion: Jenkins County, Pts. 1-5, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 29-33)
    - Core Discussion: Miscellaneous, Pts. 1-4, 1964-1972 (Box 16, Folder 34-37)
    - Core Discussion: Technical, Pts. 1-3, 1963-1972 (Box 16, Folder 38-40)
    - Core Discussion: Mechanics I, Pts. 1-6, 1963-1971 (Box 16, Folder 41-46)
    - Core Discussion: Ideas II, Pts. 1-5, 1963-1971 (Box 16, Folder 47-51)
    - Core Discussion: Practice I, Pts. 1-10, 1962-1972 (Box 16, Folder 52-61)
    - Core Discussion: Practice II, Pts. 1-4, 1962-1968 (Box 16, Folder 62-65)
    - Core Discussion: ARC 130, Pts. 1-12, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 66-77)
    - Structure Series, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 78)
    - Core Discussion Notes, Pts. 1-29, 1964-1971 (Box 17, Folder 1-29)
    - Miscellaneous Old Notes, Pts. 1-17, 1964-1967 (Box 17, Folder 30-46)
    - Professional Practice, Pts. 1-6, 1964-1967 (Box 17, Folder 47-52)
    - Human Studies: Notes (Organizational), Pts. 1-4, 1969, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 1-4)
    - Human Studies: Notes, Pts. 1-5, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 5-9)
    - Human Studies: Notes, Pts. 1-2, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
    - Human Studies: Notes, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Human Studies: Seminar Notes, Pts. 1-3, Fall 1972 (Box 18, Folder 13-15)
    - Human Studies: Seminar Notes, Pts. 1-4, Spring 1972 (Box 18, Folder 16-19)
    - Human Studies: Seminar Notes, Pts. 1-3, Fall 1971 (Box 18, Folder 20-22)
    - Human Studies: Seminar Notes, Pts. 1-2, Spring 1971 (Box 18, Folder 23-24)
    - Human Studies: Seminar Notes, Pts. 1-2, Fall 1970 (Box 18, Folder 25-26)
    - Human Studies: Seminar Notes, Spring 1970 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - Human Studies: Seminar Notes, Pts. 1-4, Fall 1969 (Box 18, Folder 28-30)
    - Human Studies: Lecture Notes, Pts. 1-3, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 31-33)
    - Human Studies: Reference Materials, Pts. 1-4, 1964-1975 (Box 18, Folder 34-37)
    - Human Studies: Opening Lectures, Pts. 1-5, 1969-1972 (Box 18, Folder 38-42)
    - Human Studies: Closing Lectures, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 43)
    - Human Studies: Transcripts, Pts. 1-3, Fall 1971 (Box 18, Folder 44-46)
    - Human Studies: Transcripts, Pts. 1-7, Fall 1970 (Box 18, Folder 47-53)
    - Human Studies: Transcripts, Pts. 1-10, Spring 1970 (Box 18, Folder 54-64)
    - Human Studies: Transcripts, Pts. 1-13, Fall 1969 (Box 18, Folder 64-76)
- Teaching: Rice University
  Barthelme was William Ward Watkin Professor of Architecture and Chairman of the Architecture Department at Rice University from February 1959 to May 1961. This series also includes an extensive collection of his memoranda to Rice faculty, including materials about his new curriculum, and related material.
  - Rice: NAAB Report (spiral bound), 1960 (Box 19)
  - Rice: NAAB Report Supplement 3 (spiral bound), 1960 (Box 19)
  - Rice: New Curriculum, Pts. 1-4, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
  - Rice: Analysis of NAAB Report, Pts. 1-2, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
  - Rice: 1959-60 Program Department of Architecture, Rice Institute, Houston, Texas, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Rice: 1959 Material, Pts. 1-60, 1959-1961 (Box 19, Folder 8-67)
  - Rice: Staff-Student Memos (Rice), Pts. 1-2, 1959-1961 (Box 19, Folder 68-69)
  - Rice: Employment References, Pts. 1-3, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 70-72)
- Architectural Projects: Drawings
  This series contains Barthelme’s architectural drawings. They fall into four categories: Studies and Preliminary Drawings; Working Drawings; Prints; and Maps and Surveys. All are large format and are stored in flat files in oversized folders. Some projects contain examples of more than one category of drawings. Note that in 1955 the name of Sweeny Negro School changed to “Carver Elementary School” and West Columbia Negro School became “Charlie Brown School.” The schools appear under both names in Barthelme’s files and in this finding aid.
  - Garage Alterations, Parents’ House, 1204 Ave. I, Galveston, 1933 (Drwr. 1, Folder 1)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - Auto Court, Galveston (proposed), ca. 1933 (Drwr. 1, Folder 1)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - Residence Alterations, 2011 Dunstan, Houston, 1933 (Drwr. 1, Folder 2)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - Galvez Motors Alterations, 23rd & Ave. P ½, Galveston, 1933 (Drwr. 1, Folder 2)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - Artillery Club, 19th & Ave. P, Galveston, 1933 (Drwr. 1, Folder 3)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 1)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - R. K. Hutchings Residence, 35th & Ave. O ½, Galveston, 1933 (Drwr. 1, Folder 4)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - L. W. Moore Residence, Galveston, 1934 (Drwr. 1, Folder 5)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 1)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
    - Prints (Drwr. 1)
  - Grafton Austin Residence, 46th & Ave. N, Galveston, 1939 (Drwr. 1, Folder 6)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - J. L. Bosquet Residence, Houston, 1940 (Drwr. 1, Folder 6)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 1)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - R. L. Toombs Residence, Galveston, 1940-1941 (Drwr. 1, Folder 7)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 1)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - Cabinet Details (project unknown), 1940 (Drwr. 1, Folder 7)
  - O. J. Lottman Residence, 3657 Olympia Dr., Houston, 1941 (Drwr. 1, Folder 8)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 1)
  - Harper Addition, Pelly, Texas (proposed), 1941 (Drwr. 2, Folder 9)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 2)
  - West Columbia School Additions, 1942-1943 (Drwr. 2, Folder 10)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 2)
    - Prints (Drwr. 2)
  - West Columbia Elementary School (proposed), 1946 (Drwr. 2, Folder 11)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 2)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 2)
  - H.W. Daily Store, 314 E. 11th, Houston, 1945 (Drwr. 2, Folder 12)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 2)
  - H. B. Vesey Store, Sweeny, Texas, 1945 (Drwr. 2, Folder 13)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 2)
  - West Columbia School Auditorium, 1946 (Drwr. 2, Folder 14)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 2)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 2)
  - West Columbia Auditorium (revised) and Shop, 1947 (Drwr. 2, Folder 15)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 2)
  - St. Rose of Lima Catholic Church, 3600 Brinkman, Houston, 1947 (Drwr. 2, Folder 16)
    - Working Drawings, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 2)
    - Prints (Drwr. 2)
  - St. Rose of Lima Catholic Church, 1947 (Drwr. 2, Folder 17)
    - Working Drawings, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 2)
  - J. L. Dargan, M.D. Offices, 1737 W. Alabama, Houston, 1948 (Drwr. 3, Folder 18)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 3, Folder 18)
  - Sweeny High School Additions, Sweeny, Texas, 1948 (Drwr. 3, Folder 18)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 3, Folder 18)
    - Prints (Drwr. 3, Folder 18)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 3, Folder 19)
  - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, Sweeny, Texas, 1950 (Drwr. 3, Folder 20)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 3, Folder 20)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 3, Folder 20)
    - Prints (Drwr. 3, Folder 20)
  - Barthelme Residence Alterations, 11 N. Wynden, Houston, 1949 (Drwr. 3, Folder 21)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 3)
  - Barthelme Residence Air Conditioning Installation, 1958 (Drwr. 3, Folder 21)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 3)
    - Prints (Drwr. 3)
  - Barthelme Residence Alterations, 1949 (Drwr. 3, Folder 22)
    - Prints (Drwr. 3)
  - Sweeny Elementary School, Sweeny, Texas, 1950 (Drwr. 4, Folder 23)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 4)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 4)
    - Prints (Drwr. 4)
  - West Columbia Elementary School, 1950-1951 (Drwr. 4, Folder 24)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 4)
    - Prints (Drwr. 4)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 4, Folder 25)
  - West Columbia Schools Miscellaneous, Chemistry Lab and Stadium Facilities, 1950 (Drwr. 4, Folder 26)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 4)
  - Negro (Charlie Brown) School Additions, West Columbia Texas, 1950 (Drwr. 4, Folder 26)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 4)
    - Prints (Drwr. 4)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 4)
  - Sweeny High School Auditorium, Sweeny, Texas, 1950-1951 (Drwr. 5, Folder 27)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 5)
    - Prints (Drwr. 5)
  - Sweeny Schools Planning, 1952 (Drwr. 5, Folder 27)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 5)
  - West Columbia High School Additions, 1951 (Drwr. 5, Folder 28)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 5)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 5)
    - Prints (Drwr. 5)
  - St. Rose of Lima Catholic Church, School Additions, 1953 (Drwr. 5, Folder 29)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 5)
  - Weingarten Store Additions, Lyons Avenue, Houston, 1954 (Drwr. 5, Folder 30)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 5)
    - Prints (Drwr. 5)
  - West Columbia Elementary School Additions, 1954 (Drwr. 5, Folder 31)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 5)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 5)
    - Prints (Drwr. 5)
  - West Columbia High School Additions, 1954-1955 (Drwr. 6)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 6, Folder 32)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 6, Folder 33)
  - Negro (Charlie Brown) School Additions, 1954 (Drwr. 6)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 6, Folder 34)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings Pt. 2 (Drwr. 6, Folder 35)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 6, Folder 36)
  - Adams Petroleum Center, Houston, 1954-1957 (Drwr. 6)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, 1954-1957 (Drwr. 6)
      - Tower, 1954-1955series (Drwr. 6, Folder 37)
      - Tower, May 1955series, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 6, Folder 38)
      - Tower, May 1955series, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 6, Folder 39)
      - Tower, Aug.-Sept. 1956series, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 7, Folder 40)
      - Tower, Aug.-Sept. 1956series, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 7, Folder 41)
      - Phase IV, 1957series, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 7, Folder 42)
      - Phase IV, 1957series, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 7, Folder 42)
  - Adams Petroleum Center, Houston, 1954-1957 (Drwr. 7)
    - Working Drawings, 1956-1957 (Drwr. 7)
    - Working Set, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 7, Folder 44)
    - Working Set, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 7, Folder 45)
    - Working Set, Pt. 3 (Drwr. 7, Folder 46)
    - Tenant Set (Drwr. 8, Folder 47)
    - Kitchen Details (Drwr. 8, Folder 48)
    - Structural Details (Drwr. 8, Folder 49)
    - Landscaping and Parking Details (Drwr. 8, Folder 50)
    - Tenant Details, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 8, Folder 51)
    - Tenant Details, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 8, Folder 52)
    - Tenant Details, Pt. 3 (Drwr. 8, Folder 53)
    - Planter Details and Studies, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 9, Folder 54)
    - Planter Details and Studies, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 9, Folder 55)
    - Special Detail Drawings (Drwr. 9, Folder 56)
  - Adams Petroleum Center, Houston, 1954-1957 (Drwr. 9)
    - Prints, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 9, Folder 57)
    - Prints, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 9, Folder 58)
    - Photostats (Drwr. 9, Folder 59)
    - Maps and Surveys (Drwr. 9, Folder 60)
  - Carver Elementary (Sweeny Negro) School Additions, 1955 (Drwr. 10, Folder 61)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings
    - Working Drawings (by E. Mattingly)
    - Prints
  - West Columbia High School Vocational-Agricultural Additions, 1955 (Drwr. 10, Folder 62)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings
    - Working Drawings
    - Prints
  - West Columbia District Office Alterations, 1956 (Drwr. 10, Folder 62)
    - Working Drawings
    - Prints
  - West Columbia Shop and School Alterations, 1957 (Drwr. 10, Folder 62)
    - Working Drawings
    - Prints
  - West Columbia High School Band Hall Additions, 1958 (Drwr. 10, Folder 62)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings
    - Working Drawings
    - Prints
  - West Columbia High School Home Management Building Air Conditioning Installation, 1958 (Drwr. 10, Folder 62)
    - Working Drawings
    - Prints
  - Highland Heights Elementary School, Houston, 1956-1959 (Drwr. 10)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, 1956-1957 (Drwr. 10, Folder 63)
    - Working Drawings, 1957-1958,Pt. 1 (Drwr. 10, Folder 64)
    - Working Drawings, 1957-1958Pt. 2 (Drwr. 10, Folder 65)
    - Prints, 1957-1958 (Drwr. 11, Folder 66)
    - Working Drawings Revised for Rebid, 1958-1959 (Drwr. 11, Folder 67)
    - Prints, 1958-1959 (Drwr. 11, Folder 67)
  - Carver Elementary (Sweeny Negro) School Additions, 1958-1959 (Drwr. 11, Folder 68)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings
    - Working Drawings
    - Prints
  - Brown, Tanner, West Columbia Elementary Additions, 1959 (Drwr. 11)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 11, Folder 69)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 12, Folder 70)
    - Prints (Drwr. 12, Folder 71)
    - Maps and Surveys (Drwr. 12, Folder 71)
  - West Columbia Junior High School Additions, 1959 (Drwr. 12)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, Pt. 1 (Drwr. 12, Folder 72)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, Pt. 2 (Drwr. 12, Folder 73)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 12, Folder 74)
    - Prints (Drwr. 12, Folder 74)
  - Kemper Fund Apartments, Galveston, 1959 (Drwr. 13, Folder 75)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, May 1959 (Drwr. 13)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, Aug. 1959 (Drwr. 13)
    - Prints (Drwr. 13)
  - Emory Spencer Residence, Rockport, Texas, 1959 (Drwr. 13, Folder 76)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 13)
    - Maps and Surveys (Drwr. 13)
  - Sun Valley Motor Lodge Additions (proposed), undated (Drwr. 13, Folder 76)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings (Drwr. 13)
  - West Columbia Senior High School, 1960-1962 (Drwr. 13)
    - Studies and Preliminary Drawings, 1960 (Drwr. 13)
    - “S” series and others (Drwr. 13, Folder 77)
    - “P” series (Drwr. 14, Folder 78)
    - “W” series (W-1 to W-27), Pt. 1 (Drwr. 14, Folder 79)
    - “W” series (W-28 to W-56), Pt. 2 (Drwr. 14, Folder 80)
    - “W” series (W-57 to W-81), Pt. 3 (Drwr. 14, Folder 81)
  - West Columbia Senior High School, 1960-1962 (Drwr. 14)
    - Working Drawings, 1960-1961 (Drwr. 14)
    - Aug. 1961 Revised (A-1 to S-8), Pt. 1 (Drwr. 14, Folder 82)
    - Aug. 1961 Revised (D series, P4), Pt. 2 (Drwr. 14, Folder 83)
    - Aug. 1961 Revised (D, EQ series), Pt. 3 (Drwr. 14, Ovs 84)
    - Aug. 1961 Revised (M, P series), Pt. 4 (Drwr. 14, Folder 85)
    - Aug. 1961 Revised (E-1 to P-3), Pt. 5 (Drwr. 14, Folder 86)
    - April 1961 (A-1 to A-22), Pt. 6 (Drwr. 15, Folder 87)
    - April 1961 (S-1 to SK40-1), Pt. 7 (Drwr. 15, Folder 88)
    - Prints (Drwr. 15, Folder 89)
    - Maps and Surveys (Drwr. 15, Folder 90)
  - Kellaway Residence Additions, 627 E. Friar Tuck, Houston, 1964 (Drwr. 15)
    - Working Drawings (Drwr. 15, Folder 91)
    - Prints, Maps & Surveys (Drwr. 15, Folder 92)
- Architectural Projects: Notes and Specifications
  Personal notes and bid specifications for many of Barthelme’s projects have survived and are contained in this series. In letter-size and legal-size format, many were originally stored with the drawings but have been separated from the oversized materials.
  - Artillery Club, 19th & Ave. P, Galveston, 1933 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - L. W. Moore Residence, Galveston, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Wells Residence, Galveston, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Austin Residence, Galveston, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Commission 139, Almeda Rd., Houston, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - R. L. Toombs Residence, Galveston, 1940-1941 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - O. J. Lottman Residence, 3657 Olympia Dr., Houston, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - St. Rose of Lima Church, Houston, 1947, Pt. 1 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - St. Rose of Lima Church, Houston, 1947, Pt. 2 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - West Columbia School Auditorium, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - J. L. Dargan, M.D. Offices, 1737 W. Alabama, Houston, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Sweeny I.S.D. 1950 Program Plumbing and Heating, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Sweeny Negro (Carver) School, Sweeny, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - St. Rose of Lima Catholic Church, School Additions, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Weingarten Store Additions, Lyons Avenue, Houston, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Carver Elementary (Sweeny Negro) School Additions, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - West Columbia High School Vocational-Agricultural Building Additions, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - West Columbia District Office Alterations, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Adams Petroleum Center Kitchen Equipment, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Highland Heights Elementary School, Houston, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - West Columbia Junior High School: Preliminary, 1959 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - West Columbia Senior High School: Streets, 1959-1962Pt. 1 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - West Columbia Senior High School: Streets, 1959-1962Pt. 2 (Box 20, Folder 23)
- Architectural Projects: Project Files
  This series contains correspondence and other files related to Barthelme’s architectural projects in letter-size or legal-size format.
  - R. L. Toombs Residence, Galveston, 1940-1941, Pt. 1 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - R. L. Toombs Residence, Galveston, 1940-1941, Pt. 2 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - R. L. Toombs Residence, Galveston, 1940-1941, Pt. 3 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - McVey Residence (proposed), 1940-1941 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Adams Petroleum Center (APC) Contractor, Legal, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, Aug. 1957–Nov. 1958 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, Oct. 1958–Nov. 1959 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, Nov. 1959–May 1960 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, Dec. 1958–Sept. 1961 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, July 1957–Oct. 1958 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, Dec. 1958–Jan. 1959 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, Feb. 1959–June 1959 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, June 1959–Nov. 1959 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - APC Contractor, Legal, Nov. 1959–Sept. 1961 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - APC Tower, Phase III notes, Aug. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - APC Tower, Phase III notes, Sept. 1956–July 1958 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - APC Tower, Phase III notes, Sept. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - APC Tower, Phase III notes, Sept. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - APC Tower, Phase III notes, Aug. 1956–Sept. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - APC Tower, Phase III notes, Aug. 1956–Sept. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - APC Tower, Phase III notes, Oct. 1956–Nov. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - APC Tower, Phase III, Aug. 1956–Sept. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - APC Tower, Phase III, Aug. 1956–Sept. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - APC Tower, Phase III, Aug. 1956–Sept. 1956 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - APC Tower, Phase III, July 1956–July 1956 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - APC Tower, Phase IV, Jan. 1957 (Box 20, Folder 49)
  - APC Tower, Phase IV, Feb. 1957–Oct. 1958 (Box 20, Folder 50)
  - Kellaway Residence, Specifications, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 51)
  - Kellaway Residence, Contractor, 1964-1965Pt. 1 (Box 20, Folder 52)
  - Kellaway Residence, Contractor, 1965Pt. 2 (Box 20, Folder 53)
  - Kellaway Residence, Contractor, 1965Pt. 3 (Box 20, Folder 54)
  - Kellaway Residence, Contractor, 1964-1965Pt. 4 (Box 20, Folder 55)
  - Kellaway Residence, Correspondence, 1964Pts. 1-9 (Box 20, Folder 56-64)
  - Kellaway Residence, Correspondence, 1965Pts. 10-15 (Box 20, Folder 65-70)
  - Kellaway Residence, Correspondence, 1965Pt. 16 (Box 20, Folder 71)
- Photographic Materials